## **Michael Ferral**

9

meferral@gmail.com



941-932-0074



<u>linkedin.com/in/michaelferral/</u>



https://github.com/meferral

Greater Nashville Area

### **SKILLS**

- SQL (PostgreSQL, JOINS)
- Python (pandas)
- Tableau
- Power BI
- Excel (VLOOKUP, Pivot Tables, PowerPivot)
- Git/GitHub
- Zoom/Slack/Teams

### **ABOUT ME**

I am an experienced leader who thrives in group settings as well as individual tasks.

My goal is to be a part of a progressive team in which I can help identify problems and provide solutions.

I am committed to sustainable practices both financially and ecologically.

#### **DATA EXPERIENCE**

Data Analyst Apprenticeship

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL| July 2021- January 2022

Six-month, intensive introduction to data analytics and business intelligence processes and tools. Learning includes communicating findings through presentations, storytelling, building reports/ creating dashboards. Tools Learned: Excel, Python, SQL, Tableau, and PowerBI

#### **PROJECTS**

- Low Income and Elderly Assistance Dashboard- group project bringing together skills in Excel (OFFSET, INDEX & MATCH)
- **Yelp Charlotte** data analysis in Yelp reviews in Charlotte NC bringing data together in PowerPivot and displaying dynamic figures mapping elements
- Lahman Baseball Data Project- independent project using PostgreSQL to explore and answer prompts in the Lahman's Baseball Database
- Basketball Power BI Dashboard- explored PowerBI using Data from the 2014-2020 NBA Basketball Season

# EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS

### NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Data Analytics Bootcamp Graduate, Jan 2021

Nashville State Community College 2014 Tallahassee Community College 2005-2007

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Vanderbilt University Campus Dining 5/2011- Present

Assistant Director May 2018-Present

- Operational Effectiveness
  - Food Management Software Implementation Designed how software infrastructure would impact operations. Software included how operations forecasted, purchased, and displayed customer facing nutrition and menus
  - Food Waste Software and Hardware Implementation- Oversaw rollout of analytics software that tracked and analyzed waste trends
  - Forecasting, Process Improvement- Took metrics from all systems and worked with analyst team to create and design operational dashboards
  - Contingency Planning- Wrote executive summary for all Vanderbilt Campus Dining Residential Operations for many phases of COVID-19
  - <u>Training & Development</u> Oversaw and created detailed trainings on all new systems rolled out so that processes could be repeatable
  - Management and New Hire Orientation Program Design- was tapped in 2021 to be on a team that focused on development, onboarding, and training for all levels in Vanderbilt Campus Dining
  - Business Analytics Analyzed and communicated data trends related to labor and food costs. Worked with 10+ operational dining managers to evaluate trends and plans for business solutions. Compiled and communicated recommended changes to dining senior leadership team.
- General Manager July 2016- May 2018
- Multi-Unit Manager June 2014- July 2016
- Supervisor May 2011-June 2014

### Steak n Shake Restaurants 8/2004-5/2011

Worked from an hourly position to a General Manager position with full store responsibility